CHRIS KOAY

https://chrisyeesk.com | chrisyeesk@gmail.com | 0448 581 566

SUMMARY

I am a software engineer with over one year of full-stack development experience, focusing on building full-stack applications using the latest technologies such as Next.js, TypeScript, C#, Node.js, PHP, Python, Drupal, and Framer Motion. I have worked for the State Library of Queensland and on a Department of Transport and Main Roads Queensland project through a private company called WorkingMouse. I also hold two AWS certifications.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer | Working Mouse, Brisbane, Australia

Nov 2024 - current

Tech Stack: Typescript, React.js, Vue.js, C#.NET, Docker, AWS, Azure, GitLab.

- Built the Property Acquisition and Disposal Record website for the Department of Transport and Main Roads (TMR).
- In charge of building the frontend and backend of the website.
- Implemented website security measures, including URI injection prevention, API input validation, multi-factor authentication, SSL, and complex password restrictions.
- Monitor website performance and identify problems using Azure Application Insights and AWS CloudWatch Logs.
- Deployment of the website to AWS ECS Fargate and setting up CI/CD on GitLab.
- Worked on PDF, word and excel file report generation using Gembox.
- Mastered the concept of platform engineering and model-driven engineering.

Full Stack Developer (Contract) | State Library of Queensland, Brisbane, Australia

Aug 2024 - Oct 2024

Tech Stack: Next.js, Typescript, Tailwind, MUI, PHP, GraphQL, Drupal, MariaDB, Solr, Docker, Lando, GitLab, Jira.

- Built the frontend and backend of the Queensland Colonial Secretary Website using Next.js and PHP.
- Maintained and fixed bugs for Oueensland Government websites.
- Speed up search queries, create faceted search, pagination, sort query results and filter query results using Apache Solr.
- Built backend API endpoints using PHP.
- Configured Drupal pages and created/edited site content using Drupal.
- Wrote a data migration script to migrate and reformat data using Drupal migrate API.

Software Engineer Intern | Sindy Labs, Melbourne, Australia

Apr 2024 - July 2024

Tech Stack: Next.js, Typescript, Tailwind, Python Fast API, Shadon, PostgreSQL, Docker, AWS ECS, GitHub, Notion.

- Contributed to building a full-stack application that uses AI to help students master a subject.
- Built a Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) Chatbot using LangChain.
- Deployed multiple docker containers application to AWS ECS and automated CI/CD workflow using GitHub Actions.
- Built Sign-in and Sign-up pages using Clerk and assign user roles (admin and normal user) to user accounts using Clerk's API.
- Created automated email templates using React Email and sent automated email using Resend.
- Built backend API endpoints for PostgreSQL CRUD operations using Python Fast API.
- Wrote end-to-end testing scripts using Playwright and Cypress and performed website load testing using Artillery.

Frontend Web Developer Intern | Webby Group, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Nov 2022 - Feb 2023

Tech Stack: Typescript, React.js, Redux Toolkit, Material UI, MongoDB, GraphQL, Node.js, GitHub.

- Contributed to building many frontend web pages for the company and took initiatives to build the backend APIs.
- Designed and built MongoDB Database. Created GraphQL Schema to interact with MongoDB Database.
- Built backend API endpoints using Express is and Node is and worked on website translation using i18next module.

Process and Equipment Engineer | Intel Corporation, Penang, Malaysia

Mar 2020 - Sep 2021

- Created a Visual C#.NET software to track equipment parts changed.
- Automated equipment log file analysis using Python and sending automated reporting emails using Python.
- Coached technicians to troubleshoot and fix Intel CPU manufacturing equipment.

Automation Engineer Intern | Advanced Energy Industries, Shenzhen, China

Nov 2018 - Jan 2019 & Nov 2017 - Jan 2018

- Automated an arc testing process by building a machine using PLC and VB.NET, resulted in 20% reduction in cycle time.
- I built the electrical control box to store the PLC controller, circuit breaker, power supply and relays.
- I worked with a supplier to build the hardware of the machine.

EDUCATION

Master of Information Technology (Specialization: Computing) The University of Melbourne

Jan 2022 - Dec 2023

Relevant courses: Internet Technologies, Algorithms & Complexity, Programming and Software Development, Database Systems & Information Modeling, Software Modelling & Design, Distributed Systems, Software Processes & Management, Advanced Database Systems, Software Project, Introduction to Machine Learning, Al Planning for Autonomy, Computer Vision, NLP

Bachelor of Mechanical Engineering (Honours) Monash University

Jan 2016 - Dec 2019

Relevant courses: Engineering Mobile Apps, Programming for Engineers, Robotics, Final Year Project, Electrical Circuits, Electromechanics, Advanced Engineering Mathematics, Engineering Mathematics, Accounting for Managers

PROJECTS

Portfolio Website - https://chrisyeesk.com

2024

Tech Stack: Next.js, Typescript, Tailwind CSS, Aceternity UI, Framer Motion and Shadon.

• My personal portfolio. The AI assistant chatbot is built using LangChain and OpenAI api. The domain was purchased through AWS Route 53 and deployed to AWS EC2 using Nginx.

Chris' AI Assistant - https://chris-assistant.com

2024

Tech Stack: Next.js, Typescript, Tailwind CSS, LangChain, OpenAI api and Shaden.

• Chris' AI Assistant is an RAG AI chatbot. It allows people to ask questions about my skills, work experience and educational background. The domain was purchased through AWS Route 53 and deployed to AWS EC2 using Nginx.

Final Year Software Project (University of Melbourne, Melbourne, Australia)

2023

Tech Stack: React.js, Redux Toolkit, Node.js, MongoDB, Confluence

- Designed and built a full-stack application for an Australian Basketball Team.
- Deployed the full-stack application to AWS EC2 and set up GitHub CI/CD workflow.
- Set up Firebase and MongoDB database.
- Created backend API endpoints using Node.js.
- Wrote testing scripts using React Testing Library and Jest.
- Designed website UI using Figma.

Multiple-user Shared Whiteboard Desktop Application (University of Melbourne – Distributed Systems Subject)

2023

Tech Stack: Java

Designed and built a desktop app where users can collaboratively draw, insert shapes, erase objects etc.

CERTIFICATES

- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate (Apr'25)
- AWS Certified Developer Associate (Mar'24)

REFERENCE

Mankit Au

Manager at State Library of Queensland mankit.au@slq.qld.gov.au 0413 757 327

Aaron Kane

Senior Developer at State Library of Queensland aaron.kane@slq.qld.gov.au 0478 764 773